Guide to the Gregg Zachary Showstopper!: papers, 1989-1993 1989-1993
Department of Special Collections
Zachary, Gregg Pascal, collector. Showstopper!: papers,
1989-1993
M1299
Zachary, Gregg Pascal, collector
12 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Contains research files, notes, audiovisual materials, notebooks, and manuscripts of Gregg Zachary's book Showstopper, documenting the history of the Microsoft.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Gregg Pascal Zachary, 2002.
Biography
G. Pascal Zachary is a senior writer for The Wall Street Journal. Splitting his time between London and Berkeley, California, Mr. Zachary is also a contributing editor of the newsmagazine In These Times and a columnist for Technology Review.
He has published two technology-related books -- Showstopper (1994), on innovation at Microsoft, and Endless Frontier, a biography of Vannevar Bush, the organizer of the Mahattan Project.
His latest book, "The Global Me: New Cosmopolitans and the Competitive Edge," is a study of how rich nations handle ethnic, racial and national diversity in their societies and a celebration of multicultural identity in the New Economy. It was published in July 2000 by Public Affairs Books.
Scope and Content
Contains research files, notes, audiovisual materials, notebooks, and manuscripts of Gregg Zachary's book Showstopper, documenting the history of the high technology field.
Collection Contents
- Series 1. Subject files
  - ABRASH, Mike (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ALLCHIN, Jim (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ALSOP, Stewart (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Analysts (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - AYCOCK, Ellen (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - BALCIUNAS, John (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - BALLMER, Steve (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - BELL, Gordon (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - BENNETT, Julie (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - BIRRELL, Scott Ian (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - BROWN, Jeff (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Build Lab (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - BROOKS, Fred (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bugs (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - BUTZI, Paul (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Cairo (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - CARON, Johan (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - CATHCART, Steve (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Chicago (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - CHAN, Chuck (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Chronology (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - CHURCHES, Larry (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - CLIGGET, Mark (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - COMAFORD, Christine (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Contract (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Crystal Computer Systems (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - CUSTER, Helen (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Customers (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - CUTLER, David W. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - CUTLER Family (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - DAVIS, Jim (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - DAY, Bob (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - DAY, Terri (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - DIAMOND, Kent (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Digital Equipment (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - DUNIE, Moshe (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - DUNCAN, Mitch (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Email (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Pam EDSTRM (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Engineering (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - FELTON, Matt (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - FENWICK, Thomas (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - FOGELIN, Eric (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Free Press (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - FREYTAG, Asmus (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - GLASS, Mike (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - GATES, William H. (Bill) (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - GLASS Memos (drek) (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - GOETTER, Ben (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - GOURD, Roger (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - GREGG, Ken (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - NAVEEN, Jain (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - HALUPTZOK, Patrick (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - HALUPTZOK, Chenoa (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - HARGROVE, Karen (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - HARTENECK, Ralf (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - HAVENS, Darryl (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - HAVENS, Jeff (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - HEINEN, Roger (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Hoppers (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - HOWELL, Jane (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - HORNE, Jim (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Hungarian (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - I860 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - IBM (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Index (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Intel (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - KAHKI, Jawad (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - KELLY, Jim (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - KENZEN, Neil (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - KIMURA, Gary (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - KIRZNER, Rikki (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Languages (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Last "Weekend" (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Edith Lewis Free Press (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - J. LAZARUS (NT) (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - LENZMEIR, Chuck (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - LETWIN, Gordon (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - LINN, Joe (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - LIVEDOTI, Don (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - LOGAN, Keith (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - LUCOVSKY, Cindy (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - LUCOVSKY, Mark (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - LUDWIG, Scott (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Lustbader (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - MANHEIM, Jonathan (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - MANHEIM, Leigh (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - MARITZ, Paul (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - McJOHN, Bill (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - McLEREN, Don (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - McSHERRY, Nancy (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Microsoft Financials (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - MILLER, Robert (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - MILLER, John (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Misc. Notes Showstopper (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - MIPs (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - MOORE, Walt (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - MUGLIA, Bob (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - MYHRVOLD, Nathan (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - NEUPERT, Peter (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - NTFS (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - NT Ships (Reactions) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Microsoft NT (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - OEMs (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - O'LEARY, Mike (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - OLYNYK, Kirk (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Oracle (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Olive T (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - OSTERMAN, Larry (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Outlines & Proposals (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - OSTERMAN, Valerie (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - PARCHERN, John (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - PARSELL, Stu (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - PDC (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - PEDERSON, Leif (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - PERAZZOLI, Lou (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - PETERS, Carol (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - PETERS, Tom' (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - PIEPER, Roel (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - PORTER, Trevor (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Press Releases NT (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - NT: Press Coverage (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Programming (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Pro Sports Club (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - RASHID, Rick (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - READERMAN, David (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - REISWIG, Lee (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Reviews (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - RINNE, Bob (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - ROWE, Steve (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - RUBIN, Darryl (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Russell (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Sam Fox Publishing Company (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - SCHULMAN, Andrew (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - SCHMIDT, Eric (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - SCHRIEBER, Benn (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - SELTZER, Joyce (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Showstopper Book Proposal (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - SHANNON, Kyle (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Ship Countdown (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Shaw, Lin (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - SHEEDY, Charlotte (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - SHORT, Rob (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - SILVERBERG, Brad (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - SIDOROFF, Donald (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - SMITH, Lee (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - SNIPP, David (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Software: General (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Software: Languages (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Software: Personal Computers (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Somasegar (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - SPENCER, John (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Status Reports (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - STORK, Carl (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - STOWELL, Therese (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - THOMPSON, Dave (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - TREADWELL, David (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - VACHON, Andre (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - VAN DYKE, Cliff (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - VALENTINE, Brian (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - WALKER, Dwayne (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - WATSON, Colin (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - WEISER, Manny (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - WELD, David (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Wendy (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - WHITE, Arden (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - WHITMER, Chuck (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - WILLMAN, Bryan (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - WILLOUGHBY, Lon (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - WILSON, Callie (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Winblad (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - WINER, David (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - WONG, Gilman (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - WOOD, Steven (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - WSJ (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Ed. Yourdon's (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - ZBIKOWSKI, Mark (Box 2, Folder 92)
- Series 2. Miscellaneous Papers
  - Microsoft Internal Docs (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Papers (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Papers (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Series 3. Clippings
  - Clippings (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Clippings (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Clippings (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Series 4. Manuscript
  - SHOWSTOPPER! Draft (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - SHOWSTOPPER! Gally Proofs (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Series 5. Books
  - Microsoft Windows NT Systems Guide (Box 3)
  - Custer, Hellen. Inside Windows NT (Box 3)
  - Anklam, Cutler, Heinen, MacLaren. Engineering a Compiler (Box 3)
- Series 6. Videotapes
  - Microsoft Studios Bill Gates-Plenary Speech, Fall Comdex, 1991 11/4/91 1:15:00 (Box 5)
  - Microsoft Studios Tech Talk Seminar #9, NT Subsystem Technology - Steve Wood, 7/16/91 1:00:00 (Box 5)
  - Microsoft Studios Win NT C2 Security - DAP Training, Week One "NFTS File Systems" Tom Miller, 8/26/93 1:20:00, Tape 12 of 15 (Box 5)
  - Microsoft Studios Win 32 Professional Developers Conference, Speaker: Dave Cutler, 7/7/92 1:14:00 (Box 5)
  - Microsoft Studios Win 32 Professional Developers Conference, Keynote Address: Bill Gates, 7/6/92 57:00, Tape 1 (Box 5)
  - Microsoft Studios Microsoft Windows NT - Atlanta, Bill Gates Entire Keynote Address5/24/93 1:09:00 (Box 5)
  - Microsoft Studios Win32 Professional Developers Conference,, General Session 8, Windows NT I/O Subsystems: Darryl Havens, San Francisco, CaliforniaJuly 6-8 1992 (Box 5)
  - Microsoft Studios Win32 Professional Developers Conference, General Session 9, Windows NT Networking: Dave Thompson, San Francisco, California July 6-8 1992 (Box 5)
  - Microsoft Studios Win32 Professional Developers Conference, General Session 4, Win32 Graphics Device Interface: Chuck Whitmer, San Francisco, California July 6-8 1992 (Box 5)
  - Microsoft Studios Win32 Professional Developers Conference, General Session 16, Windows Futures: Jim Allchin, San Francisco, California July 6-8 1992 (Box 5)
  - Information at Your Fingertips (Box 5)
  - Bill Gates WABC-TV Channel 7, This Week with David Brinkley (Box 5)
  - Microsoft Broad Research TV Advertising Nov 1994-March 1995 (Box 5)
- Series 7. Notebook
  - Microsoft Day 3/10/1993 (Box 3)
  - Neil Konzen -- Bill Gates (dinner) (Box 3)
  - Microsoft Visit #2 7/25/1991 -- Brad Silverberg (includes Borland contracts) (Box 3)
  - Steve Baumer Interview 3/2/1989 (Box 3)
  - Visit to Microsoft 7/24/1991 (Box 3)
  - Microsoft Day #2 3/11/1993 (Box 3)
  - Microsoft Day #3 3/12/1993 (Box 3)
  - Misc. torn notebooks (3) (Box 3)
- Series 8. Diskettes
  - Microsoft NT 3.1 Installation Discs (3) (Box 3)
  - Greg, Wong, Day Int, 3/4" Floppy (Box 3)
  - Abrash & Rashid Interviews, Micro Floppy Copies, 3/4" Floppy (Box 3)
- Series 9. Audiocassettes
  - Caron 7/13/93 (Box 4)
  - Abrash/Cutler (A) Cutler(B) (Box 4)
  - Cutler (A & B) 9/7/93 (Box 4)
  - Dave Culter 8/17/93 (Box 4)
  - Cutler pt. 2 8/17/93 (Box 4)
  - D. Cutler 8/24/93 (Box 4)
  - Day: testing 8/3/93 (Box 4)
  - Bill Gates 11/14/91 (Box 4)
  - Gates 7/24/91 (Box 4)
  - Gates 10/22/91 (Box 4)
  - Gates 8/3/93 (Box 4)
  - Bill Gates 10/13/93 (Box 4)
  - Patrick Haloptzoki (Box 4)
  - Havens, D. 7/30/93 (Box 4)
  - Jeff Havens 8/18/93 (Box 4)
  - Leigh Manheim (Box 4)
  - Lou Perazzoli. 9/14/93 (Box 4)
  - Lazarus/Manheim 7/7/93 (Box 4)
  - David Treadwell 8/3/93 (Box 4)
  - Wood 7/13/93 (Box 4)